DIEGO VILLABRILLE SECA

Navia (Asturias), Spain · +34 626 738 841 diego.villabrille@uji.es · LinkedIn Profile · Portfolio

SUMMARY

Video game programmer finishing my bachelor's degree. I focus on gameplay programming, AI techniques and virtual reality. I have used C#, Kotlin, Java, C, C++, Python, JavaScript and SQL. I have also used game engines such as Unity or Unreal Engine. My other academic interests are game studies and multidisciplinary game research in general, as well as UI and UX design.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MAY 2021 - JULY 2021

Collaboration scholarship for research in GIANT-UJI research group

Department of Computer Science and Engineering, Jaume I University - Castelló (Castellón), Spain

Researched artificial intelligence evolutionary techniques applied to multi-action games in collaboration with the Research Group on Machine Learning for Smart Environments from Universitat Jaume I.

- Programmed several genetic evolutionary algorithms and tested them on an existing game.
- Developed a simple but flexible additional test game from scratch.
- Performed step by step performance analysis of each algorithm.

JANUARY 2020 - APRIL 2021

Student researcher in DiNaVi project from ITACA-UJI research group

Jaume I University - Castelló (Castellón), Spain

Collaborated on the project *Videogame narratological design: a proposal of narrative creation structures, styles and elements with a post classical influence* from the Research Group on Technologies Applied to Audiovisual Communication from Universitat Jaume I.

- Written the paper The briefness of the playable instant in the virtual worlds: Spatiality and temporality in SuperHOT and SuperHOT VR which has been published in a peer reviewed journal.
- Researched about the narratological structure of several video games.

VOLUNTEER WORK

SEPTEMBER 2020 - JUNE 2021

Student mentor at Jaume I University - Castelló (Castellón), Spain

Mentor for a group of first year students from the Video game design and development degree.

JANUARY 2018 - JUNE 2019

Game events staff at UJI Game Experience - Castelló (Castellón), Spain

Participated in organizing and executing events for video game fans, students and industry professionals.

OTHER EXPERIENCE

MAY 2019

Second place in the Strategy card game AI competition (CEC-C09) at IEEE CEC 2019

Programmed an Al agent that was able to play Legends of Code and Magic as part of a 6 people team.

EDUCATION

CURRENT

Video game design and development degree (90% finished)

Jaume I University - Castelló (Castellón), Spain

Degree aimed at training video game developers with solid programming knowledge to develop video games while also including some courses on other areas of game development.

Ernest Breva 2018/2019 Academic Excellence Award for having the best academic record of my class. Graduated with honors in 24 courses (70% of the courses taken). GPA of 9.25 out of 10.

JUNE 2020

Creative media and game technologies exchange program

Saxion University of Applied Sciences - Enschede, The Netherlands

One semester exchange program with courses on game programming and game design. I focused in areas such as networking and evolutionary algorithms.

GPA of 8.8 out of 10.

DECEMBER 2019

Digital simulation and game engineering technology exchange program

Shawnee State University - Portsmouth (OH), USA

One semester exchange program including programming and media courses, with a focus on game engines, graphics and operating systems.

Director's List Fall 2019 Award for achieving maximum grade on all courses during the semester. GPA of 4.0 out of 4.0.

LANGUAGES

English, advanced level (Certificate in Advanced English from Cambridge Assessment - Pass at Grade A).

Spanish, native speaker.